Guide to the United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Oral History Collection OH.019
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Oral History Collection
1962-1994
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
OH.019
4 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 3 cassette boxes, 1 half manuscript box, a CD box, and 13 items in a shared cassette box.
112 audiocassettes
16 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel
The labor union now known as District 65, UAW, was organized in 1933 by Arthur Osman and in 1938 became Local 65 of the United Retail and Wholesale Employees of America, CIO. Though at first primarily composed of Jewish workers, the union expanded to include persons of various geographical and ethnic backgrounds from the retail and manufacturing sectors, clerical personnel, salesclerks, writers, editors, technicians, and lawyers. The United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Oral History Collection is audio recordings and transcriptions for over 30 interviews with union members dating from 1980 to 1994, as well as audio recordings of an Executive Council meeting from October 12, 1982. This collection also contains audio recordings of speeches by Martin Luther King, Jr. dating from 1962 to 1967 and a Martin Luther King, Jr. memorial service from 1971.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collected by the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives; dates unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 1979.015.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by interviewee last name.
Historical Note
The labor union now known as District 65, UAW, was organized in 1933, by Arthur Osman and in 1938 became Local 65 of the United Retail and Wholesale Employees of America, CIO. In 1948, Local 65's leadership refused to sign the Taft-Hartley Act's non-communist affidavits, and Local 65, seceded from its parent union and the CIO but rejoined in 1954 as District 65 of the RWDSU (Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union). In 1969, differences, including the union's opposition to the Vietnam War, led to District 65's disaffiliation from the RWDSU and the formation of the National Council of Distributive Workers of America. In 1979, District 65 joined the United Automobile Workers. Though at first primarily composed of Jewish workers, the union expanded to include persons of various geographical and ethnic backgrounds from the retail and manufacturing sectors, clerical personnel, salesclerks, writers, editors, technicians, and lawyers.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access CDs for audiovisual materials in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Related Materials
United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Records (WAG.006)
Scope and Contents
The United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Oral History Collection contains interviews in the form of audio recordings and transcriptions for over 30 union member oral history interviews dating from 1980 to 1994. Topics include union evolution from the 1960s to the 1980s; March on Washington; the Red Scare; Frank Cherry; African-Americans in the union; lack of women in union negotiations; trade work in the Depression Era; and the formation and evolution of the Camera Club. An audio recording of a union Executive Council meeting from October 12, 1982 is also in this collection, as well as of speeches by Martin Luther King, Jr. dating from 1962 to 1967 and a Martin Luther King, Jr. memorial service from 1971.
Oral history.; Labor unions -- New York (N.Y.); Labor unions -- Organizing -- United States.; United Automobile, Aircraft, and Vehicle Workers of America. District 65
- Patricia Adkins, November 18, 1980; cuid274
  Scope and Contents
  Interview topics include union evolution from the 1960s to the 1980s.
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 8)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Walter Bailen, undated
  - Interview Notes (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Leon Becker, March 11, 1980
  Interview topics include March on Washington in 1963, the Red Scare, and Frank Cherry.
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 1, 21A-B)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Frank Brown, May 11, 1982 and June 4, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 10A-B)
  - Audiocassette Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 10A-C)
- Carl Butler, March 24, 1988; cuid275
  Interview topics include African-Americans in the union, and lack of women in union negotiations.
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment Cassette Box 1, Audiocassette 44A-B)
  - Access Copy (Box Access CD Box 1, Cd Butler)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Henry Cannon, November 4, 1980
  Interview topics include evolution of union politics since 1946.
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 4)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Nick Carnes, March 1, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 22A-C)
- Zeke Cohn, undated
  - Original Recordings (Box 3, Audiocassette 36A-B)
  - Audiocassette Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 36A-B)
- Morris Doswell, December 2, 1980
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 37A-B)
  - Audiocassette Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 37A-B)
- Hy Drucker, Aug 19, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 23)
- Frank Engleberg, May 20, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 38)
- Al Evanoff, July 22, 1984
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 24A, Box 3, Audiocassette 24B-D)
  - Audiocassette Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 24A-D)
- Executive Council Meeting, October 12, 1982; cuid276
  - Original Recordings (Box 3, Audiocassette 29A-B)
  - Access Copy (Box Access CD Box 1, Cd 29A-B)
- Silvia Feiner, November 11, 1980
  Interview topics include contractual progress since 1960, and union consumer services.
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 2)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Joe Finn, November 11, 1980; cuid277
  Interview topics include pro-1960s militancy, Taft / Hartley class consciousness, and minorities in unions.
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 3)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Nollie Harstein, September 9, 1982 and September 24, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 39A-B)
  - Audiocassette Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 39A-B)
- James Hodges, November 18, 1980; cuid278
  Interview topics include organizing in the McCarthy period; state of democracy in 1965; and March on Washington in 1963.
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 5)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 9)
- J. Johnson & T. Weekly, undated
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 33)
- Martin Luther King Memorial, January 15, 1971
  - Original Recording -- 1/4 inch reel (Box 1)
  - Access Copy (Box Access CD Box 1)
  - Audiocassette Copy (Box Shared Tamiment Cassette Box 1, Audiocassette 50-51)
- Martin Luther King Speeches, 1962-1967; cuid279
  - Original Recording -- 1/4 Inch Reel (Box 1)
  - Audiocassette Copy (Box Shared Tamiment Cassette Box 1, Audiocassette 46-49)
  - Access Copy (Box Access CD Box 1, Cd 46-49)
- David Livingston, December 4, 1981 -- February 25, 1982
  - Tape 1, cuid43708 (Box 2, Audiocassette 9A)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Duration: 92 minutes
  - Tape 2, cuid43709 (Box 2, Audiocassette 9B)
    Duration: 72 minutes
  - Tape 3, cuid43710 (Box 2, Audiocassette 9C)
    Duration: 75 minutes
  - Tape 4, cuid43711 (Box 2, Audiocassette 9D)
    Duration: 64 minutes
  - Tape 5, cuid43712 (Box 2, Audiocassette 9E)
    Duration: 55 minutes
  - Tape 6, cuid43713 (Box 2, Audiocassette 9F)
    Duration: 77 minutes
  - Tape 7, cuid43714 (Box 2, Audiocassette 9G)
    Duration: 95 minutes
  - Tape 8, cuid43715 (Box 2, Audiocassette 9H)
    Duration: 63 minutes
  - Audiocassette Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 9A-G)
- David Livingston, September 4, 1994
  - Tape 1, cuid43707 (Box Shared Tamiment Cassette Box 1, Audiocassette 45A)
  - Tape 2, cuid43716 (Box Shared Tamiment Cassette Box 1, Audiocassette 45B)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Sam Neuberger, October 13, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 25A-B)
  - Audiocassette Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 25A-B)
- Ngubo and A. Montoya, undated
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 32)
- Jack Paley, July 15, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 26A-C)
  - Access Copy (Box Access CD Box 1, Cd Paley 1-5)
- Harry Respler, October 31, 1980
  Interview topics include trade work in the Great Depression.
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 7A-B)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Milton Reverby, January 26, 1981 -- January 4, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 11A-C)
  - Audiocassette Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 11A-C)
- Cleveland Robinson (Winston), November 23, 1980 -- January 7, 1983; cuid152
  Interview topics include members' involvement in meetings, and problems and politics in 1950s.
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 12A-C, 35, Box 2)
  - Access Copy (Box Access CD Box 1, Cd Robinson, 1-13)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 11)
- C. (Cleveland) Robinson and J. Lowery, undated; cuid151
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 31)
- Gideon Rosenblut, May 19, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 27A-B)
- Morris Rosenzweig, January 27, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 40A-B)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Ed Roth, May 24, 1990
  Interview topics include the formation and evolution of the Camera Club.
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 13A-B)
  - Transcript (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Audiocassette Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 13A-B)
- Pete Stein, June 4, 1982, December 9, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 41A-D)
- Bernie Stephens, April 1983
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment Cassette Box 1, Audiocassette 42B, Box 3, Audiocassette 28A-B)
  - Audiocassette Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 28A-B)
- M. Stepp and J. Mangone, undated
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 34)
- J. Turner and J. Dav, undated
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 30)
- Irving Weinstock, February 15, 1982
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment Cassette Box 1, Audiocassette 43A-B)